Guide to the June D. Drake photographs
Oregon Historical Society Research Library
- Locations, 1860-1953; Series 3; 2,864 photographic prints
  - Mount Angel, 1890-1940; Subseries 3.2
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Band, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Buildings--Public, 1908; 1912; 1927 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Includes images of the train depot and city hall.
    - Businesses--Identified by name--Abiqua Tuff Rock Manufacturing, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Businesses--Identified by name--Bank of Mt. Angel, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Businesses--Identified by name--Benedictine Press, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Businesses--Identified by name--Hotel Mt. Angel, circa 1923 (Box 8, Folder 5a)
    - Businesses--Identified by name--Beginning with "Mt. Angel", circa 1931; undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Businesses--Identified by name--N. Schmaltz & Sons General Warehouse, circa 1920 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Businesses--Identified by name--P. S. Smith Furniture, circa 1925 (Box 8, Folder 7a)
    - Businesses--Unidentified--Bakery - Saloons, circa 1908-1940 (Box 8, Folder 7b)
    - Celebrations--Flax Festival, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Celebrations--St. Mary's Church dedication, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Celebrations--St. Mary's Church dedication, interiors, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Churches--Parish church and parsonage, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Fire department, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Abbey and gardens, circa 1930 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Abbey church, interior, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Architectural drawing of buildings, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Referred to on drawing as St. Benedict's Abbey and Mount Angel College.
    - Mount Angel Abbey--St. Benedictine Monastery, 1890; 1908 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      Includes photographs taken by George Weister.
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Celebrations--Corpus Christi celebration, circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Celebrations--Golden Jubilee celebration of Titular Abbot Adelhelm Odermatt, OSB, 1916 September (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Celebrations--New abbey dedication, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Celebrations--Other, 1934; 1939 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Farm and conservatory, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Fire, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      The fire destroyed the monastery and Mount Angel College.
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Monastery and seminary (oversize material), 1908 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Monks, identified, circa 1930; 1939; undated (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
    - Mount Angel Abbey--Monks, unidentified, circa 1932 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Organizations--Fraternal--Knights of Columbus retreat, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Organizations--Other--Staff of the Pacific Star, 1913-1914; undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Schools--Mount Angel Academy and Normal School, circa 1920-1931 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Schools--Mount Angel Academy--Sports teams--Girls, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Schools--Mount Angel College--Band, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Schools--Mount Angel College--Choir, 1931; 1932 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Schools--Mount Angel College--Faculty and students, 1929; 1931 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Schools--Mount Angel College--Sports teams, 1910-1931 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Schools--St. Mary's School, 1926-1934 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Views, circa 1908; 1925 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Salem, 1899-1935; Subseries 3.3
    - Bridges, 1913; 1926 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of dedication of railroad bridge, 1913.
    - Bridges (oversize material), 1913 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      Includes photographs of dedication of railroad bridge.
    - Buildings--City Hall, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Buildings--Courthouses--Marion County Courthouse, circa 1920; undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Buildings--Courthouses--State Supreme Court, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Buildings--Hospitals, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Buildings--Methodist Old Folks Home, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Buildings--Oregon Fairview Home, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Buildings--Oregon State Hospital, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Buildings--Oregon State Hospital--State Insane Asylum, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Buildings--Oregon State Penitentiary, 1920-1926 (Box 9, Folder 9a)
    - Buildings--Organizations, 1925; undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Buildings--Post office, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Buildings--Public library, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Buildings--Railroad station, circa 1900; 1925 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Buildings--Residences, 1913; undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Buildings--State Capitol, circa 1913; 1920 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Buildings--State Capitol (oversize material), circa 1920 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Buildings--State Capitol (oversize material), 1920 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Buildings--State Capitol fire, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Buildings--Unidentified, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Businesses, circa 1920-1926 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Celebrations--Parades, circa 1900; 1913 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Churches, circa 1930 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Crime scene, 1926 May (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Oregon State Fair--Buildings and grounds, circa 1920-1925 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Oregon State Fair--Buildings and grounds (oversize material), circa 1925 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Oregon State Fair--Exhibits, circa 1925 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Parks--Willson Park, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Schools--Public schools, circa 1926 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Schools--Oregon State School for the Deaf, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Schools--Oregon State Training School, circa 1920 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Schools--Willamette University, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - State officials, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Street scenes, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Stunt bicycle rider, 1899 September (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Silver Falls State Park, circa 1900-1934; Subseries 3.4
    Arranged alphabetically by place or feature name.
    - Double Falls, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Double Falls (oversize material), 1923; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Drake Falls, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Drake Falls (oversize material), 1923; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Lower North Falls, 1906; 1923 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Lower North Falls (oversize material), 1923; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Lower South Falls, 1906; 1932 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Middle North Falls, undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - North Falls, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - North Falls (oversize material), 1923; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - South Falls, circa 1906-1934 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - South Falls (oversize material), 1928; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - South Falls in winter, circa 1900; 1931 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - South Falls in winter (oversize material), 1931 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Twin Falls, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Twin Falls (oversize material), 1923; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Upper North Falls, circa 1906; 1923 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Upper North Falls (oversize material), 1923; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Winter Falls, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Winter Falls (oversize material), 1923; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Other park scenes, circa 1928 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Other park scenes--Al Faussett's boat ride over South Falls, 1928 July 1 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Other locations, circa 1865-1953; Subseries 3.5
    Arranged alphabetically by state and place name.
    Photographs taken prior to 1900 are copy photographs made by Drake from original photographs taken by unidentified photographers.
    - Idaho, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Idaho--Lapwai, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
      Includes Henry Harmon Spalding gravesite.
    - New York--Staten Island--Wagner College, undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Oregon--Abiqua Basin, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Oregon--Abiqua Creek, undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Oregon--Abiqua Creek--Monument to the Battle of the Abiqua, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Oregon--Abiqua Creek Falls (oversize material), undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Oregon--Albany, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Oregon--Breitenbush Hot Springs, undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Oregon--Brownsville--First flouring mill built in Oregon, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Oregon--Cascade Locks, 1926; circa 1930 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Oregon--Depoe Bay, undated (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Oregon--Drift Creek Falls, undated (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Oregon--Galice, circa 1910 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Oregon--Gervais, circa 1865 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Oregon--House Mountain Rock, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Oregon--Lafayette--Government Locks, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Oregon--Lake Labish, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Oregon--Lebanon, circa 1928 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Oregon--Linn County--Providence Church and Joab Powell monument, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Oregon--Marquam, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Oregon--Mill City, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Oregon--Molalla, circa 1925 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Oregon--Monitor--Crime scene, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Oregon--Mount Hood, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Oregon--Mount Jefferson and Olallie Lake, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Oregon--Mount Washington, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Oregon--Mulino, circa 1920; 1928 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Oregon--Multnomah Falls, circa 1910 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Oregon--Newport, circa 1900 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Oregon--Niagara, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Oregon--Oakbridge and Westfir American Legion Cascade Post No. 64, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Oregon--Oregon City, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Oregon--Polk and Yamhill County line--George Gay house, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Oregon--Polk and Yamhill County line--George Gay house (oversize material), 1912 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Oregon--Portland, circa 1900; 1920 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Oregon--Pudding River flood, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Oregon--Scio, circa 1928 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Oregon--Scotts Mill, circa 1926; 1950 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Oregon--Selah Springs, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Oregon--Selah Springs (oversize material), 1909-1910 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Oregon--Three Sisters, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Oregon--Turner, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Oregon--Wallowa Lake Park, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Oregon--Wilhoit, 1902-1909 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Oregon--Wilhoit--Wilhoit Coal Mine, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Oregon--Wilhoit--Wilhoit Springs tent camp (oversize material), undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Oregon--Woodburn--McLaren Boys Home, circa 1915 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Oregon--Yoder--T. H. Sconse and cottonwood tree, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - South Dakota--Wessington, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Washington--Grand Coulee (oversize material), undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Washington--Grand Coulee Dam, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Washington--Ilwaco, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Washington--Skagit City, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Washington--Woodland, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Washington, D.C.--Capitol building, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified locations--Bridges, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Unidentified locations--Buildings and structures, 1951; undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Unidentified locations--Camping sites, circa 1900-1920 (Box 10, Folder 41a)
    - Unidentified locations--Churches, circa 1930; undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Unidentified locations--Creeks, rivers, lakes, dams, and waterfalls, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Unidentified locations--Monuments, rocks, and fields, undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Unidentified locations--Residences, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified locations--Residences--Log cabins, 1912; circa 1920 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Unidentified locations--Road and camp, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Unidentified locations--School classes, undated (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Unidentified locations--Towns, undated (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Unidentified locations--Vistas, undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Agriculture, circa 1887-1955; Series 4; 657 photographic prints
  Photographs of crops, farms, harvesting techniques, and livestock in the Silverton area of Oregon taken by June D. Drake. Photographs taken prior to 1900 are copy photographs made by Drake from original photographs taken by unidentified photographers.
  - Botanical specimens, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Crops--Beans, circa 1955 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Crops--Blackberries and boysenberries, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Crops--Cabbage, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Crops--Celery, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Crops--Celery (oversize material), undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Crops--Corn, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Crops--Flax, 1912-1941 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Crops--Flax (oversize material), circa 1940 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Crops--Flowers, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Crops--Flowers--Cooley's Gardens--Family and store, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Crops--Flowers--Cooley's Gardens--Employees, circa 1925 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Crops--Flowers--Cooley's Gardens--Fields, 1935-1951 (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - Crops--Fruit, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Crops--Fruit--Spraying, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Crops--Grain--Fields, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Crops--Grain--Fields (oversize material), 1910 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Crops--Grain--Harvest with horse-drawn equipment, undated; Includes hand-painted photograph. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Crops--Grain--Harvest with horse-drawn equipment (oversize material), undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Crops--Grains--Harvest with motorized equipment, circa 1908 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Crops--Grains--Shocked (oats and wheat), circa 1900 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Crops--Grains--Shocked (oats and wheat) (oversize material), circa 1900 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Crops--Grains--Shocked (oats and wheat) (oversize material), circa 1900 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Crops--Hay, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Crops--Hops, circa 1887-1928 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Crops--Hops--Horst hopyard (oversize Cirkut print), circa 1934 (Folder Oversize 1)
  - Crops--Loganberries, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Crops--Mint, circa 1930 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Crops--Mint (oversize material), circa 1930 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Crops--Mint (oversize material), circa 1930 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Crops--Onions, circa 1930 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Crops--Onions (oversize material), circa 1930 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Crops--Plums, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Crops--Root vegetables, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Crops--Raspberries, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Crops--Strawberries, circa 1930; 1940 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Crops--Strawberries (oversize material), undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Crops--Sunflowers, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Crops--Tomatoes, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Crops--Walnuts and filberts, circa 1930 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Crops--Walnuts and filberts (oversize material), circa 1930 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Farms--Identified by location, circa 1925 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Farms--Identified by owner, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Farms--Unidentified buildings, undated (Box 11, Folder 33-34)
  - Farms--Unidentified fields, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - "Fresh Air Children", 1913 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Land clearing, circa 1910; 1939 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Livestock--Bees, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Livestock--Dairy cattle--Identified by farm, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Livestock--Dairy cattle--Bulls, circa 1915; 1941 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Livestock--Dairy cattle--Cows, 1915; undated (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - Livestock--Dairy cattle--Cows (oversize material), 1915 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Livestock--Dairy cattle--Five-legged calf, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Livestock--Dairy cattle--Grazing, undated (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - Livestock--Frogs, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Livestock--Goats, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Livestock--Hogs, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Livestock--Hogs (oversize material), undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Livestock--Horses and mules, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Livestock--Oxen, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Livestock--Poultry--Chickens, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Livestock--Poultry--Geese, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Livestock--Poultry--Geese (oversize material), undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Livestock--Poultry--Pheasants, circa 1907; 1924 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Livestock--Poultry--Pheasants--J. K. Mounts Pheasantry (oversize material), circa 1907 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Livestock--Poultry--Turkeys, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Livestock--Sheep, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Livestock--Sheep (oversize material), 1934 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Livestock--Sheep (oversize material), 1934 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Livestock--Machinery, circa 1925; 1941 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Portable cannery, 1933 October 22 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Windmills, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Davenport family, 1868-1953; Series 5; 70 photographic prints
  This series contains photographs taken and collected by Drake of members of the Homer Davenport family of Silverton, Oregon, and the related Geer family. Homer Davenport (1867-1912) was a political cartoonist of national prominence who was born near Silverton and who is also credited with bringing Arabian horses to the United States. Photographs taken prior to 1900 are copy photographs made by Drake from original photographs taken by unidentified photographers.
  - Timothy, Florinda (Geer), and Homer Davenport, 1868; circa 1900 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Geer Homestead--Riding whip tree, circa 1910; 1953 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Geer Homestead--Riding whip tree (oversize material), circa 1953 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Homer Davenport, circa 1887-1912 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Homer Davenport's funeral, 1912 May 20 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Homer Davenport's parrot, circa 1915 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Photographic reproductions of Homer Davenport sketches, 1891; 1894 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Timothy Davenport and second wife, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - R. C. Geer, Mary C. (Willard) Geer, and an unidentified young woman, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Said Abdallah and Habib, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
    Abdallah was Homer Davenport's Arabian horse trainer, and Habib was Davenport's Arabian horse.
  - Said Abdallah (oversize material), undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Native Americans, 1908-circa 1930; Series 6; 31 photographic prints
  - Chemawa Indian School, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Portraits, 1908; 1909; circa 1930 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Lumber industry, 1890-1948; Series 7; 566 photographic prints
  - Camps--Bridge Creek Camp, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Camps--Silver Falls Timber Company, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Camps--Silver Falls Timber Company (oversize material), undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Oversize material
  - Camps--Silverton Lumber Company, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Camps--Unidentified, 1910; circa 1925; undated (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  - Camps--Unidentified (oversize material), 1910-1920 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Camps--Unidentified--Cooks and dining hall, 1910; undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Employees--Children, circa 1900 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Employees--Loggers, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Forest fire, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Logs, 1900-1942 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Logs (oversize material), undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Mills--Employees, equipment, and activities, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Mills--Employees, equipment, and activities--Silver Falls Timber Company, circa 1910; 1917 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Mills--Employees, equipment, and activities--Silver Falls Timber Company (oversize material), circa 1910 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Mills--Employees, equipment, and activities--Silverton Lumber Company, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Mills--Identified by name, 1890-1903 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Mills--Identified by name--John G. Lais sawmill, Silverton, Oregon, 1908-1909 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Mills--Johnson and Ek (oversize material), 1892 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Mills--Identified by name--Silver Falls Timber Company, circa 1906-1947 (Box 13, Folder 18-20)
  - Mills--Identified by name--Silver Falls Timber Company (oversize material), 1917 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Mills--Identified by name--Silverton Lumber Company, 1908-1920 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Mills--Unidentified, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Mills--Unidentified--Sawed and milled lumber, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Mill ponds, circa 1905-1916 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Silver Falls Timber Company--First and last load of logs from Abiqua Basin, 1913 August 25; 1938 September 6 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Silver Falls Timber Company--Office, 1917 March 3 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Silver Falls Timber Company--Office (oversize material), undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Silver Falls Timber Company--Retail yard, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Silverton Lumber Company--Office, 1907; 1920 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Standing timber, 1906; 1927 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Timber felling, 1909-1948 (Box 13, Folder 30-31)
  - Transportation--Horses and oxen, 1898-1909 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Bucking and loading logs--Silverton Lumber Company, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Grading tract with plow and horses, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Loading logs, circa 1930 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Silver Falls Timber Company, 1916-1917; 1938 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Silver Falls Timber Company (oversize material), circa 1915 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Silverton Lumber Company, 1911; 1913 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Silverton Lumber Company (oversize material), 1910-1938 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Steam donkey, 1911 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Timbers cut by Lockyear Lumber Company, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Tracks and bridges, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Transportation--Railroads--Truck, 1910-1948 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Military, 1918-1940; Series 8; 42 photographic prints
  - Bands, camps, cooks, and officers, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Oregon State Militia, 1918; 1940 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Oregon State Militia (oversize material), 1918 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Portraits--Identified, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Portraits--Unidentified military men, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Portraits--Unidentified military men (oversize material), undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Transportation, 1890-1950; Series 9; 170 photographic prints
  - Airplanes, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Automobiles, circa 1910-1920 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Automobiles--Cascade Highway, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Bicycles, circa 1900; 1929 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Bridges, circa 1929 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Bridges--Covered, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Buses, circa 1930 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Horses, circa 1910 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Horses--Horse and buggy, circa 1910 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Horses--Horse-drawn hearse, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Horses--Horse-drawn wagons, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Roads, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Ships, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Stage coach, 1905 April 14 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Trains, 1890; circa 1910; 1912 (Box 15, Folder 21)